Rakeshkumar Thummar

 ♥ Brisbane, Queensland, Australia
 rakeshthummar2012@gmail.com
 0493658596

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rakeshthummar2012/

SUMMARY

Highly skilled and collaborative iOS Developer with more than 6 years of experience in iOS development. Design and development of User interface applications, integrating with numerous databases and client server applications of iOS using Cocoa Touch. Seeking challenging software engineer or developer position in dynamically growing company, and expand my skills and knowledge to actively contribute through development and integration of new technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Sr. iOS Developer

Microloop IT Solutions LLP

April 2020 - December 2022, India

• At MICROLOOP IT SOLUTIONS i have played multiple roles like Developer, Project Coordinator and Team leader to provides guidance and instruction to a working group about a project or portfolio of projects. Managing the day-to-day activities of the team. Motivating the team to achieve organisational goals. Developing and implementing a timeline to achieve targets. Complete project in tight deadline. Delegating tasks to team members. Always trying to improve team's and my skill for robust, scalable and maintain good quality of code.

Sr. iOS Developer

Codezee Solutions Pvt. Ltd

August 2018 - March 2020, India

- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ To design and build advanced applications for the iOS platform.
- · Client Interaction.
- To collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design and ship new features.
- · To generate wireframes.
- To design, develop, test and implement an iOS application as well as continue production.

Jr. iOS Developer

Dignizant Technology

July 2015 - June 2018, India

- \cdot Design and build applications for mobile devices running Apple's iOS operating software
- \cdot responsible for designing and coding the base application, ensuring the quality of the application, fixing application bugs, maintaining the code, and implementing application updates.
- · Collaborating with the design team to define app features.
- · Identifying potential problems and resolving application bottlenecks.
- Fixing application bugs before the final release.
- · Publishing application on App Store.
- · Maintaining the code and atomization of the application.
- · Designing and implementing application updates.

EDUCATION

Masters In Computer Application

Gujarat Technological University · India · 2014

Bachelors in Computer Application

Saurashtra University · India · 2011

SKILLS

Technical Skills:

Integrations:

- ✓ Socket.io

Soft Skills:

- ✓ Leadership, Teamwork, Creative, Analytical, Problem solving ability.
- **ℒ** Experience developing in Agile planned projects.
- ✓ Source control (Github, Gitlab)
- ✓ Project management skill.

- ✓ Excellent communication skills and have experience working within a customer facing environment.

Projects:

- => Dustland Runner (App Link: https://apps.apple.com/hk/app/dustland-runner/id1616478668?l=en)
- => Scratchie (App Link: https://apps.apple.com/au/app/scratchie/id1572053207)
- => Ballet Workout (App Link: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/ballet-workout/id1447342760)
- => Lyrical.ly (App Link: https://apps.apple.com/in/app/lyrical-ly-lyrical-video-maker/id1468462592)

Visa Status:

I have 485 visa with full rights to work in Australia.